The rules keep changing.
I've been rehearsing every possible outcome.
Once this thought arises, there is no more room for right or wrong.
I am resolved to sever this flood
so that my soul can break free from mediocrity,
from loneliness and distinction.
One more step and you'll fall into madness.
Don't fall down.
I look towards the top.
Chase !
Refined to perfection.
Never retreat, no matter the danger.
I dare to defy the heavens !
Always overcome the obstacles,
ignite the seas with blood,
bloom through trials and tribulations.
Even the sharpest thorns
will be reduced into ashes.
What is there to fear ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
4 years later
Fallen Moon Village
Planet Ran Yun
If someone breathes the immortal mist on Qilian Peak,
they'll be healthy for 10 years !
Look at me,
have I ever been sick in all these years ?
Zhou Family's youngest son
Villager of Fallen Moon Village
Really ?
How amazing !
Wang Ping,
if only you could take a breath of that mist...
Wang Ping
I...
I'll have my father take me to the peak to breathe the immortal mist !
4 years ago, the heavens became angry,
and the immortal mist disappeared.
All of you listen to me,
it's better to learn martial arts together.
When we grow up, we can travel the martial world with our swords !
Travel the martial world with our swords !
Alright,
come back for dinner !
Hurry up,
stop playing !
Alright,
We will continue today's tournament
after dinner !
Go !
Let's go !
Quick !
If someone breathes the immortal mist on Qilian Peak,
they'll be healthy for 10 years !
Little Wang,
were you having a martial arts tournament
with my son again ?
Greetings, Uncle Zhou.
Zhou Dahan
Villager of Fallen Moon Village
You're handsome and polite,
you are indeed the child of a craftsman.
Let's go,
take me to your father to have some furniture made.
Dad !
Uncle Zhou is here.
Brother Wang,
my son is getting married.
His house
is missing a set of furniture.
I'll need to trouble you, Brother Wang.
This is the deposit.
Okay,
come back in 3 days.
No problem !
He hunted such a big deer !
Dad...
The medicine is very bitter...
Dad,
are there really Immortals on Qilian Peak ?
Drink it now,
the medicine must be drunk while hot.
Dad,
when can Ping'er stop drinking this medicine ?
Soon.
Liu Mei's medicine, along with my thunder Origin Soul
are slowly unraveling it.
After 4 years of gentle nurturing,
the resentment has mostly faded.
On the outside, he appears no different from an ordinary child
but if the treatment is interrupted, he will revert.
It seems it will still take a long time to completely heal him.
His past is severed,
he has no memories.
For him,
this is a new life.
4 years...
Fallen Moon Village is very similar to my hometown...
If back then, I had become an ordinary carpenter
as my father wished,
would my life really have been like this ?
Senior Sun.
Don't call me Senior.
I finally found the thing
you asked me to find.
With Celestial Ascension Fruits of the Northern Domain of Allheaven,
let alone a giant beast,
if a demon dragon swallowed it,
it would be unconscious for 100 days.
The 17 families of the Northern Domain
are always wherever traces of this fruit appear.
With my meager cultivation level,
this is the most I can do for you.
You can go get the rest yourself.
Thank you
for your help.
It's just a transaction.
After you pass away,
I will take your ashes
back to Planet Dark Moon in the Alliance Star System
and bury them in the village at the foot of Heaven Mountain.
Don't worry,
I won't forget.
Who are you ?
I...
Ping'er,
this is Grandpa Sun.
Greetings, Grandpa Sun.
He called me
Grandpa ?
What a beautiful fruit !
The fruits flew away !?
Grandpa,
you can do magic ?
These things are not for a child like you.
Why ?
Can they be eaten ?
It's for the big beasts in the mountains that don't sleep.
Big beasts ?
How big ?
Bigger than the Old Yellow Ox at the village entrance ?
And why don't they sleep ?
Will eating these fruits make them dream ?
Are you going to let him keep asking questions like this ?
Grandpa, have you ever seen them dream ?
It's rare to see you at a loss like this.
This child truly is endearing.
He has only 15 years of lifespan left.
Now at the end of his life, he has no one to turn to.
This is also a kind of karma for me.
Grandpa.
There's an empty house next door.
If you don't mind this rustic village,
then please stay.
Really !?
Ping'er likes Grandpa Sun !
Grandpa Sun, please stay !
Please stay, Grandpa Sun.
I never imagined that I, Sun Tai, after my life of wandering,
would still find a place to settle down.
Awesome !
Grandpa Sun is staying !
Grandpa,
hurry up !
Tell me a story about the big beasts !
Alright.
5 years later
Little rascal,
why don't you spend some time with your father
instead of coming over to see me ?
I'm not going back.
Aunt Zhang has come again.
Here to play matchmaker again ?
You don't have to worry.
Look, Grandpa Sun,
in the past 3 years,
Aunt Zhang has come exactly 12 times.
Why do all the aunts of the village
want a bite of my father
as if he were a piece of sweet cake ?
Brother Wang, look at this !
These stitchings, the thoughtfulness...
The Zhao Family's daughter stayed up several nights for this.
She said that
once married, she would treat Ping'er as her own child !
Even if you don't think of yourself,
you need to think of your child !
He can't continue without a mother's love forever.
I have no such intention for now.
Oh, my good brother,
listen to me,
it's been 9 years since you brought Ping'er to our village.
Back then I was still a young unmarried girl
and now my own child is running all over the village !
A house without a woman in it
doesn't feel like a home !
Am I right,
Brother Wang ?
Father,
I'm starving.
The child is hungry,
let's stop this matter here.
Fine.
I guess I wasted my time.
Brother Wang,
if you ever change your mind,
make sure you come to me first !
This little Ping'er truly has
quite a temper growing up.
He got that from his father.
He is among the gentlest in our village !
Otherwise,
why would so many young ladies come to visit him ?
Dad,
you...
Don't overthink it,
Aunt Zhang is just being kind.
Since Er Hu's got a stepmother,
he doesn't get enough to eat
and gets scolded all the time.
Take your medicine first.
Ping'er will stay with you,
you won't be lonely.
When Ping'er grows up,
I'll take care of you into your old age
and let you enjoy a good life !
Grandpa Sun,
I ran much faster today than yesterday, didn't I ?
Of course.
Don't you plan to let this child cultivate the Dao ?
With your cultivation level,
he's sure to have a smooth path
and will have an advantage over even the best cultivation families.
I named him Ping
because I wish for him to live an ordinary, peaceful life.
I will not let him cultivate the Dao.
In his lifetime, I will never let him experience
the cruelty and the dangers of the cultivation world.
But this child was born very talented...
I will not let him cultivate.
Never.
Don't ever
mention this again.
Why exactly ?
It seems like he is hiding something...
Dad,
Grandpa Sun,
what are you talking about ?
Ping'er,
it's time to take your medicine.
But a mortal's lifetime will go by quickly...
A short lifespan of only a few dozen years...
Grandpa Sun,
what did you want to show me today ?
Today,
I will let you witness
the secret art of my sect that roams the sea of stars.
Grandpa Sun,
are you an Immortal !?
This old man started cultivating at 7
and was revered as the Head Elder for centuries.
Today, I pass on to you our sect's secret technique...
the Pulse Fixing Art !
This is a Corpse Puppet.
A Corpse Puppet ?
What is that ?
It's an avatar that can fight thousands of enemies for you.
This big guy is a bit scary.
A cultivator
controls Life and Death,
and defies the will of the heavens.
Your illness and lifespan
can both be rewritten.
If you cultivate,
you will no longer have to suffer in this frail mortal body.
You will be immune to heat and cold,
and free from all sickness.
No... no...
I promised Dad
that I will never cultivate.
If you and I don't speak of it,
no one will know.
Ping'er can't lie to Dad.
I can't make Dad sad !
Just like your father...
stubborn to the bones.
According to the ancient texts,
it's said...
After that,
Ping'er started going to school.
He still took his medicine on time every day.
To dispel Ping'er's resentment,
I no longer need to use my spells.
It feels like a huge burden has been lifted off my shoulders.
In this mundane, ordinary life,
my Dao Heart
has grown even more harmonious and insightful.
The Life and Death Domain
seems to be undergoing a transformation.
But the road ahead is still shrouded in mist.
I can only wait quietly.
As for Sun Tai,
he never truly gave up.
He's constantly finding new ways to try to lead Ping'er to cultivate.
At birth, human nature is inherently good.
Condense yin energy from the primordial dust
and gather the corpse's soul in the Dantian.
This is the great path of the Corpse Puppet.
Grandpa Sun !
10 years of springs and autumns
passed in the blink of an eye.
What must come
has finally arrived.
Grandpa Sun !
Grandpa Sun...
Take one more sip.
Looking back over half a lifetime,
the man in blue robes has grown old.
It seems that
life has far more
disappointments
than satisfactions.
Thinking back on the journey...
I was the son of an Elder of the main branch of the Corpse Sect,
Sun Tai
Young
a thousand years old Soul Transformation cultivator.
Everyone said I was favored by the heavens
with a smooth path ahead.
Sun Tai,
accept your miserable fate.
In just a hundred years,
I became
a mere slave in the Allheaven Star System
spat upon by everyone.
I was outraged,
always wondering
which step had gone wrong
in leading me to lose everything.
In these last ten or so years of my life,
I finally understood.
I...
among thousands of choices
simply walked toward my own fate.
Looking back now,
we only live once
so you should
sing when you gain and rest when you lose.
Sorrow and resentment are fleeting.
Now, for me
all joys and sorrows,
all grudges and loves,
Note: reference to the ancient scripture Platform Sutra
are illusions in the Bodhi mirror.
I dismiss them with a smile.
Don't worry,
I will fulfill
my promise.
Between Life and Death...
It turns out the difference was so fleeting after all...
Grandpa Sun !
Escort the coffin !
Old Sun was all alone
but at least he had his adopted grandson Ping'er to see him off.
Grandpa Sun,
my carving isn't as good as Dad's.
Sun
Tai's
Tomb
Inscribed
by
his
grandson
Wang
Ping
Please don't be offended.
Senior Sun,
I have collected your ashes.
I will not fail to do
what I promised you.
Rest in peace.
19 years...
Fallen Moon Village saw one generation off
and welcomed another.
Of the neighbors from back then,
30% are gone.
A mortal's life
is nothing more than this.
Brother Wang,
almost 20 years have passed in a flash.
So fast...
I still remember how you looked when you first brought Ping'er here.
And now, you're leaving.
Brother Zhou,
thank you for all your trouble over these years.
The child has grown up,
it's time to take him out
to see the world.
I suppose my second daughter
just wasn't meant to have that fortune.
Wang Ping,
you...
Will you come back ?
I probably won't.
I hate you, Wang Ping !
Second sister !
Take care !
Brothers Wang,
take care !
Take care !
Take care.
Have a safe trip !
Dad,
why are women always such a hassle ?
Especially Zhou Ruotong.
Don't you like her ?
I wouldn't say that.
It's just that when she cries,
in here...
It feels a bit uncomfortable.
Dad,
where are we going next ?
First, we'll see the mountains
and how they soar majestically,
touching the heavens while reaching the earth.
Like Qilian Peak ?
No.
We'll go see mountains higher than Qilian Peak,
much farther away.
Go ahead and take a look
on the other side of the mountain.
The cycle of Life and Death
is like wisps of smoke and drifting clouds,
See if the wind is blowing
across the sea.
A lush tree always grows
from a tender shoot.
gone without a trace.
I have long learned
the many aspects of Death.
But I have little experience
with the essence of Life.
That tree shields you
from half of the cold.
I thought the Life and Death reincarnation cycle was the ultimate reality.
But Sun Tai's final words
made me realize
The scent of the herbs and the smoke
have drifted away from the stove
that the Life and Death reincarnation cycle is merely the continuation of karma.
Sow the cause, reap the effect.
whose fire has warmed up
half of your lifetime.
Effect arises from the cause.
The fate of all living beings is based on this.
I watch you smile
as you run back to me.
And above the Life and Death Domain,
there is still the great Dao of Karma.
That cry, however,
came out slowly.
The 19 years in Fallen Moon Village were a quiet living.
I’ve walked through this world with you
and listened to the joys and sorrows of the mountains.
Sun Tai's matter is over
and karma is now clear.
The path ahead is becoming clearer.
As I count the falling leaves, as spring warms,
another year has flown by.
I took Ping'er and left Fallen Moon Village
heading into the wider human world of mountains and seas.
Let the mountains and rivers of heaven and earth
If you were to travel alone through the mountains and rivers
for half your life as if attending a banquet,
wash his soul clean
to reveal his true self.
I would wait for you beneath the locust tree
with a warm bowl of food.
A mountain is not a mountain,
it's a place to climb and gaze into the distance.
The landscape is lush
with blooming flowers.
Water flows over the cliff
into the sea.
Who will the rain
fall onto next ?
The moon sees through
the traveler’s weathered eyes.
He has traveled through mountains and seas
but longs for a moment of reunion.
The wind blows through the window
stirring memories of days gone by filled with laughter and joy.
All I see are
the joys and sorrows we've shared.
I'll take you on a journey through the mortal world,
as autumn fades and spring returns.
As the snow falls from the eaves,
I hope this letter finds you well.
I’ll wait for you under the locust tree,
having weathered the storms of our journey so far.
Looking back, the smell of the food
hasn't changed.
Take your time.
I’ve walked through this world with you
and listened to the joys and sorrows of the mountains.
As I count the falling leaves, as spring warms,
another year has flown by.
I’ll wait for you under the locust tree,
having weathered the storms of our journey so far.
Looking back, the smell of the food
hasn't changed.
Take your time.
Traversing
the mortal world
Lyrics: Su Qia & Zhun Wei
Composer: Mao Liang
Singer: Hu Xia